Have a nice day.
一路順風
Mr. Tideman.
泰德曼先生
Mr. Lasky? AW3 Marty Padanski.
萊斯基先生？ 我是馬蒂.派德斯基
Mr. Lasky? I'm Richard Tideman's executive assistant.
萊斯基先生？我是 理查德.泰德曼的行政助手
- Glad to know ya. Are you going with me? - No.
-幸會.你和我一起來嗎？ -不
Mr. Tideman just wanted to see you off.
泰德曼先生是來送你的
- Is that him in the car? - Yes.
-車裡的人就是他？ -是的
Well, we've never met. Can I introduce myself?
我們還沒見過面呢. 能否讓我自我介紹一下？
It isn't necessary, Mr. Lasky.
不必了，萊斯基先生
As I said, he came to see you off.
我說了，他是來送你的
Well, thank him for me.
那替我感謝他吧
Take a look, sir.
看那邊，長官
Arizona Memorial.
亞歷桑那紀念館
She's now resting in 33 feet of water in an upright position.
她現在沉睡在33英尺的水下
There were only 289 survivors.
當時只有289名生還者
Russian trawler.
俄羅斯拖撈船
What's it doing?
它在幹嘛？
Not doing much fishing!
反正不是在捕魚！
I'll take it, sir.
我來拿吧，長官
Mr. Lasky, I'm Commander Dan Thurman, executive officer.
萊斯基先生，我是指揮官 丹.瑟曼，執行參謀
- Welcome aboard. - Thank you.
-歡迎登艦 -謝謝
Now follow me to the Bridge.
請隨我到指揮塔去吧
Stand clear, spot 3.
三號點空曠
Helo-733, rotating.
733號直升機請起飛
- Give me 25 knots of wind over the deck. - Aye, Captain.
-迎風25節船速行駛 -是，艦長
- All ahead full. - All ahead full, aye.
-全速前進 -全速前進
- Indicate 1 00 R.P.M. - Indicate 1 00 R.P.M. Aye, sir.
-轉速100 -轉速100，長官
Central Bridge, all ahead full, 1 00 R.P.M.
指揮塔，全速前進，轉速100
- Continue fixed wing recovery. - Aye, Captain.
-繼續調整航向  -是，艦長
Let's bring the Kag aboard.
讓凱格降落
Victor-200, your signal is Charlie.
維特200，這裡是查理
- Set 52, Tomcat.
-「雄貓」52號位 -「雄貓」52號位
T-minus 30 seconds.
30秒後降落
Tomcat 200. I'm on approach and lining up.
「雄貓200」正準備登艦
Gear coming down.
起落架已放下
200, slightly right.
「雄貓200」，稍微往右轉
Gear down and locked.
起落架鎖定
Add power. Power.
加速…
All indicators green.
可以降落
Hold there.
穩住
Hold it. Slightly left.
穩住，往左偏轉
In the groove. Looks good.
位置正好
In the port, Cat 1. Get below. We still have aircraft to land.
一號機，到左弦機庫. 我們還有飛機要降落
I hear you're on assignment from Tideman Industries
聽說泰德曼公司 派你去國防部…
to the Defense Department, right?
有這回事嗎？
- Yeah, that's right. - What is your job, Mr. Lasky?
-是的，沒錯 -你是做什麼的，萊斯基先生？
- I'm a systems analyst. - Oh, efficiency expert, right?
-我是個系統分析家 -效率專家，對嗎？
Yeah, you could say that.
也可以這樣說
- That's a quick change in the weather. - Yeah!
-天氣變化得可真快 -是的！
Sure is.
沒錯
- Hi, Kag. - It's getting a little strange out there, boys.
-嗨，凱格 -外面的天氣有點不對勁
- Welcome aboard, Mr. Lasky. - Thank you, Captain.
-歡迎登艦，萊斯基先生 -謝謝你，艦長
- Are we headed for a squall? - Not an official one.
-是不是要有暴風雨？ -這不算什麼
Sir, this is Commander Damon, operations officer.
先生，這是戰術指揮官達蒙
- How do you do, Mr. Lasky? - Fine, thank you.
-你好，萊斯基先生 -幸會
And Lieutenant Perry, officer of the deck.
甲板指揮官佩瑞上尉
- How do you do, sir? - Good, sir.
-你好，先生 -幸會
Mr. Lasky is going to be taking a look
萊斯基先生這次來…
at how we do things here aboard the Nimitz.
是想看看「尼米茲號」的運轉情況
- We'll give you whatever help we can, sir. - Thank you.
-我們會盡量協助你的 先生 -謝謝
Our departure was delayed two days
在你們那神秘老闆的 一再請求下…
- at the request of your mysterious boss. - I'm sorry about that, Captain
-我們的航程拖延了兩天 -我對此深感抱歉，艦長
but I'm afraid Mr. Richard Tideman is as much a mystery to me
不過對於我和其他 所有人來說…
- as he is to the rest of the world. - Two days.
-泰德曼先生也同樣神秘 -整整兩天
Perhaps the fact that Tideman helped design and build this ship
也許是因為這艘航母 是泰德曼設計建造…
affords him some special privileges.
因此他才會有特權
Corporal Kullman will escort you while you're aboard ship.
庫爾曼下士負責 協助你的工作
- Right this way, sir. - Oh, Mr. Lasky?
-這邊請，長官 -萊斯基先生？
I'd be delighted if you'd join me for dinner.
我很希望和你 一起共進午餐
Thank you, Captain. I'd like that.
謝謝你，艦長.我很榮幸
Am I mistaken, or was Black Cloud's forecast this morning
「黑雲」說，今天會晴空萬里
- for clear skies and sunshine? - I'll bet he wishes it wasn't, sir.
-是不是我聽錯了？ -看來他失算了，長官
Hand me that weather report, please.
把氣象報告拿給我看一下
Thank you.
謝謝
What do you think it is?
你看看這是什麼？
It wasn't there on the morning run.
今天早上時還沒有的
Check all projection lenses, and if it's not there, check all receivers.
查找所有顯示器，如果沒有 就查所有的接收器
Aye, aye, sir.
是，長官
The Nimitz. Who's that?
「尼米茲號」.那是誰？
- A Russian trawler. - What's he want?
-一艘俄羅斯拖撈船 -他想幹嘛？
A big fish!
想來條「大魚」！
You've been assigned Navigator's inport cabin, sir.
你就住在海軍內務船艙 長官
Connects with Commander Owens, our air wing commander.
隔壁就是歐文斯空軍指揮官
Your luggage has been delivered, sir.
你的行李都在裡面了，長官
I'll be just outside, sir, if there's anything you need.
如果你有什麼事 我就在外面
Thank you.
謝謝
Hello?
有人嗎？
"'Pacific At War, Commander Richard T. Owens.''
(太平洋戰爭) 理查德.歐文斯指揮官
Very well.
好的
We're having communication problems with the incoming flights.
我們與待降飛機的 聯繫有困難
- What do you mean? - It's interference from the storm, sir.
.什麼意思？ -暴風雨造成的干擾，長官
- Get Black Cloud up here. - Yes, sir.
-快讓「黑雲」來我這裡 -是，長官
Sunshine and clear skies.
晴空萬里
- Anything else you'd like to see? - I beg your pardon.
-你想看什麼東西？ -對不起
What the hell are you doing in my cabin?
你在我的房間幹嘛？
I'm terribly sorry.
真的很抱歉
You're Commander Owens. I'm Warren Lasky.
你一定就是歐文斯指揮官了. 我是沃倫.萊斯基
They put me next door.
他們安排我住在隔壁
Mr. Lasky, the one thing we cherish aboard a ship is privacy.
萊斯基先生，我們在船上 都很注重隱私
Maybe it's because we get so damn little of it.
本來我們的隱私就少得可憐
I understand. I hope you'll forgive me.
我明白.請原諒我的失禮
You know, from what I've read, your manuscript is very good:
我剛才看了一下 你寫的東西很不錯
I mean, really very good.
真的非常好
Thank you. You a historian, Mr. Lasky?
過獎.你是歷史學家 萊斯基先生？
I'm a little bit of everything, I guess. I work for Tideman Industries.
我對什麼都有點好奇. 我是為泰德曼公司做事的
What exactly is your job aboard this ship?
你到船上來幹嘛？
Very simply, I look at the way you people do things
很簡單，我是來觀察 你們的運轉情況
and if I can think of any alternatives
看是否有更好的改善辦法…
I write it up and submit a report to the Department of Defense.
最後遞交一份報告給國防部
Think you'll find some?
你懧為自己能找到嗎？
Well, there are always alternatives, Commander.
辦法總會有的，指揮官
Mr. Lasky, please don't look for them in here.
萊斯基先生，請你不要 在我的房間找
Excuse me.
對不起
Boss, Kag's here.
艦長，凱格來了
George, any further word from Stanton?
喬治，有斯坦頓的消息嗎？
We know he's inbound, but we can't talk to him. His radios are garbled.
他正在返航，但我們聯繫 不到他.他的無線電受到干擾
Just wish he had more experience.
真希望他多點經驗
Yes, Captain. Yes, sir. He's right here.
是的，艦長，他在這裡
- Kag? - Yes, Skipper?
-凱格？ -是，艦長
- How many planes have you got in the air? -Just one, sir.
-你還有幾架飛機在天上？ -就一架，長官
- Our newest pilot, Stanton. - Well, get him aboard as fast as you can.
-是我們新來的飛行員斯坦頓 -盡快讓他降落
- I want to get out of this weather. - Right away, Skipper.
-我要盡快擺脫這鬼天氣 -好的，艦長
- He wants him down now. Keep trying. - Corsair, 41 2.
-艦長讓他立刻降落，快點 -「海盜船412號」
Air Ops Primary, try again on 41 2. See if you can reach him.
空軍指揮塔，繼續搜索412 看能否找到他
Take a look at the scope, sir.
看看顯示屏，長官
The water temperature's down five degrees
溫度下降了5度…
and even the barometer's giving improper readings.
氣壓計的讀數也很不正常
It should be down, and it's way up.
讀數應該降低 現在卻是升高的
- What the hell is that? - It seems to have a cycle, sir.
-那是什麼鬼東西？ -它似乎還有個光環，長官
One run it's there, the next one is clear.
時而模糊，時而清晰
One run it's there, the next one is clear. I've never seen anything like it.
時而模糊，時而清晰. 我從沒見過這種情況
Turn those destroyers around and head them back to Pearl Harbor.
讓那些驅逐艦返航回珍珠港
- No need for them to go through this. - Yes, sir.
-沒必要讓他們也摻合進來 -是，長官
Keep it in the wind till we get that Corsair aboard.
我們繼續等待「海盜船」著落
It's one of our new pilots.
那是我們其中一個新飛行員
All units in Romeo Alpha, this is Kilo Bravo.
所有信號燈注意 這裡是指揮塔
This is 4 1 2. I have an unsafe hook indicator. Over.
我是412.飛機釣鉤失靈
4 1 2, roger. Unsafe hook. Recycle your hook.
明白，412.繼續嘗試放下釣鉤
Negative. I've tried that.
不行.我試過了
4 1 2,your transmission's poor. Say your fuel's state.
412，你的信號很弱. 報告你的燃料狀況
Captain Boss, that Corsair's in real trouble. Can't get his tail hook down.
艦長，「海盜船」有大麻煩. 它不能伸出釣鉤
- I think we better take him in the barricade. - Rig it!
-看來只有設攔截網了 -設網！
Air Ops, tri-flight. On the flight deck!
後勤人員都到飛行甲板上！
We have an A-7 Corsair in trouble. Can't get his hook down.
有一架「海盜船」攻擊機 遇上了麻煩，無法放下釣鉤
This is not a drill.
這不是演習
Repeat, this is not a drill. Now rig the barricade.!
重複，這不是演習. 快設置攔截網！
Bow deck.! Bow deck.! This is no drill.!
艦首！這不是演習！
All right.! Let's go.!
好了，快點！
Go on.! Let's hustle now.!
大家動作快點！
All personnel off the deck now.!
所有人員離開甲板！
Barricade coming up. Clear the area.!
升起攔截網，退出甲板！
Clear the flight deck.!
退出飛行甲板！
- Do you see him out there yet? - Yeah, there he is!
-你看到他了嗎？ -是的，他在那裡！
Head's up! Green deck, land aircraft.
注意！準備降落
My God. Look at that.
上帝，看那邊
Have Central come up on theJ.A.
指揮攻擊機降落
- Steady as she goes. - Steady as she goes, aye.
-平穩航行 -平穩航行，長官
Central Bridge, pick up theJ.A.
指揮塔，指揮攻擊機降落
- Aye, sir. - Where's that plane?
-長官-飛機在哪兒？
I don't see it, Captain.
我沒看見，艦長
Sound general quarters.
全體警戒
- Aye, Captain. Boatswain. - Boatswain mate. Aye, sir.
-是，艦長.水手長 -在這裡，長官
- Sound general quarters. - Aye, sir.
-全體警戒 -是，長官
General quarters, general quarters.
全體警戒
All hands, man your battle stations.
全體人員回到戰鬥崗位
Go up and forward on your starboard side, down and aft on your port side.
全體從右弦上甲板 船尾左弦待命
General quarters, general quarters.
全體警戒
Time plus two minutes.
兩分鐘
- What the hell's goin' on? - General quarters, sir. Come with me.
-怎麼回事？ -全體警戒.快隨我來
Time plus three minutes.
三分鐘
Time plus four.
四分鐘
Report when all stations are manned and ready.
所有人員準備就緒後報告
Got him right there! Comin' in! A-7 Corsair!
他在那兒！「海盜船」攻擊機！
Heads up on deck! He's in bound to the barricade.
甲板注意！他正衝向攔截網
Green jackets to the barricade.
引航員到攔截網去
We can't hear you.
我們聽不見
All right.
好了
Crash on deck! Crash on deck! All personnel respond now!
飛機降落.所有人員行動！
Let's get out there and watch for fire.!
快去查看飛機有無起火
Red shirts, front and center! Move it, move it!
消防員，快到前中甲板！
Move it!
快！
- Go back to course 3 50. - Aye, aye, sir.
-回到350航線 -是，長官
Okay! Take 'er down!
好了，降下來！
All personnel on the Flight Deck, let's turn to.
甲板所有人員，趕快行動
Blue shirts, locks and chains on the aircraft.
拖機員，把飛機固定好
Is this the last known position of our destroyers before the storm?
暴風雨之前，驅逐艦的 最後位置是在這裡？
- Yes, sir, Captain. - Skipper.
-是的，艦長 -艦長
Dan, go down and check out the Threat Board.
丹，去受損中心查看一下
- Keep me posted. - Right.
-向我報告 -好的
- Get Kag up here. - Yes, sir.
-讓凱格到這兒來 -是，長官
I want to talk to CI NPAC Fleet.
我想和艦隊通話
Captain, we're down across the board. Antennas check out, but we're off the air.
艦長，雷達搜索完畢 沒有任何發現
- Any word from our destroyers? - We aren't getting anything
-有驅逐艦的消息嗎？ -沒有他們的消息…
except some code transmissions in the 200-meter band.
只接收到一個兩百米 波長的信號
Otherwise, we're dead as a doornail.
此外，沒聽到任何動靜
- Ops, what's our radar picture? - Radar shows us clear, sir.
-雷達顯示如何？ -雷達顯示一片空白，長官
Clear? Can't you see that Russian trawler?
空白？沒看見那艘 俄羅斯拖撈船？
I have the signal officer on deck, but no visual sighting, sir.
信號指揮官去了甲板 但沒任何發現
Keep me advised. Navigator, what's our posi?
先讓我想想.領航員 我們的位置是多少？
27 0, Captain. 280 miles west of Pearl Harbor.
270，艦長.珍珠港向西280英
Oh, Dick. Launch a Hawkeye to check ship's communications
迪克，派一架「鷹眼」 去執行搜索
a Crusader to make a photo run over Pearl and put two Tomcats on ready alert.
一架「十字軍戰士」前往 珍珠港.兩架「雄貓」執行警戒
- Aye, aye, sir. - Captain! Captain!
-是，長官 -艦長！
Hey, what happened?
到底怎麼了？
Frankly, I don't know.
說實話，我也不知道
Lieutenant, have the heads of all departments
上尉，通知所有指揮官…
meet me at C.V.I.C. immediately after the launch.
午餐之後到會議室開會
Aye, aye, sir.
是，長官
- Mr. Lasky, I want you to stay with me. - Captain's off the Bridge.
-萊斯基先生，你和我一起 -艦長不在指揮室
It's a code.
這是個密碼
Can you break it, Chief?
你能把它破解嗎？
- I think someone's putting us on. - Why?
-有人似乎在蒙騙我們 -為什麼？
Because I learned this code at Great Lakes. It's ancient.
我在「五大湖」學過 這種密碼.這是個老代碼
Thanks, Chief.
謝了
Stand clear at 0 1 2. Hawkeye rotating.
012準備完畢. 「鷹眼」準備起飛
Off the bow, stand clear.
人員離開甲板
736 lifting for plane guard.
736號執行護航
Hold it! Hold it! Hold it!
別吵了！
- Go hold your own! - Who said that?
-被吵的是你 -誰說的？
Chrissakes, Chief, all we want to know is what's going on.
長官，我們只想知道 到底發生什麼事了
- Whatever it is, you'll be told. - When?
-遲早會告訴你們的 -什麼時候？
- As soon as the skipper's ready. - That's what they always say!
-等艦長弄清楚之後 -他們總是這樣說！
Hey, Ex-O, what's goin' on? Attention on deck!
嘿，到底怎麼了？大家起立！
Carry on.
坐吧
Gentlemen, we're at general quarters, because I don't have any idea what's happened.
各位，之所以全體警戒，是 因為我不知道發生了什麼事
But I don't exclude the possibility of war.
但我不排除戰爭的可能性
- A nuclear strike? - Possibility.
-核打擊？ -有可能
- Now, what action's been taken? - Well, Skipper
-你們的檢查工作進展如何？ -艦長…
there's nothing on the Threat Board
受損中心沒任何報告
and there's been no significant damage to the ship.
艦船沒有任何重大損傷
- The crew's in good shape. - Air wing is intact. First team's ready to go.
-全體人員都安然無恙 -空軍無損失.一分隊已準備待命
E-2 is now showing the area clear, and reconnaissance aircraft
E-2目前沒任何發現…
should be coming up on Pearl, sir.
偵察飛機現在應該 已到達珍珠港
The reactor is stable. All readings are normal.
反應堆穩定，所有指數正常
Capable for maximum speed, Captain.
可進行全速航行，艦長
- Lloyd. - We can transmit and receive
-勞埃德 -通訊信號正常
- but we haven't been able to reach anybody. - Why's that?
-但無法和其它艦船取得聯繫 -為什麼？
Tried everybody in the book-- CI NPAC,Joint Chiefs--
所有艦船都試過了 「辛派克號」，「聯合號」…
I even took a crack at the White House.
甚至還試著聯繫過白宮
Now, we do have some low-band transmissions--
我們接收到一些短波信號…
strictly manual stuff with very low power.
但是信號很弱
We'll have to do some retuning to transmit in that range.
我們再調整波段來試試
Get on with it!
盡快去辦！
- Ops? - All radar's up, all weapon systems check out.
-奧普斯？ -所有雷達已開啟，武器系統都檢查完畢
- We're ready, sir. - Mr. Lasky. You have anything to add?
-隨時待命，長官 -萊斯基先生
- No, sir, not at this time. - Skipper.
-現在沒有，艦長 -艦長
I have a reconnaissance report coming in now, sir.
勘測報告正在傳過來，長官
Flight level 250. Camera rolling.
飛行水平面250，攝像機開啟
There doesn't appear to be any damage. Seems to be some unusual shipping traffiic.
沒發現任何受損狀況.海港 似乎有船隻在航行
I'll make another pass for a close-up series.
我再仔細觀察一次
- Over. - E.T.A. to Nimitz, 1 2 minutes, sir.
-完畢 -偵察機12分鐘後到達「尼米茲」
Skipper, we're picking up some weird traffic on the A.M. broadcast band
艦長，我們接收到一些 奇怪的廣播信號
on the entertainment circuit, but the signal strength is very weak.
娛樂頻道傳來的 但信號很弱
Boss, I told you. I tried and tried, and I can't get Carmichael to go to sleep.
頭兒，我說過了，我很累. 我哄不了卡麥克睡覺
Rochester, that polar bear's got to go to sleep.
羅切斯特，北極熊也都睡覺了
- He's supposed to hibernate. -Jack Benny?
-他一定是在冬眠 -傑克.賓尼
Where is he now?
他現在在哪兒？
Sittin'up in bed, readin' Esquire.
坐在床上看 (時尚雜誌)
Esquire? Well, take it away from him.
(時尚雜誌)？ 沒收他的雜誌
Oh, come now, boss. He's been around.
拜託，頭兒.他正看得爽呢
Lloyd, tape and monitor all transmissions.
勞埃德，監聽所有信號
Ops, I want a closer look on all air, surface and subsurface contacts
奧普斯，監視內海陸空 所有的通信訊號…
within 250 miles of this ship.
監視半徑250英里
Dick, put some tankers and a medium-sized strike force on a 30-minute alert.
迪克，派幾架飛機執行 半小時性戰鬥巡邏
- Aye, aye, sir. - Any questions?
-是，長官 -還有問題嗎？
Skipper, the ship is still at general quarters. Request permission to go to condition 3.
艦長，艦船還在全體警戒. 請求恢復第三秩序
Granted. I'll be on the Bridge. I want answers.
批准.我就在指揮塔 我想盡快得到答案
Attention on deck!
全體起立！
Secure from general quarters. Set condition 3.
全體警戒解除. 恢復第三秩序
- I stand relieved. - Very well.
-交接完畢 -好的
- Bridge. - Captain's on the Bridge.
-指揮塔 -艦長來指揮塔
Captain, C.I.C. reports a surface contact bearing 3 50 at 1 30 miles.
艦長，雷達室報告，130英里 350方位發現通訊信號
- I want an I.D. on the surface contact. - Yes, sir.
-立即確懧這個信號 -是，長官
- Launch the ready alert. - Aye, sir.
-派出飛機警戒 -是，長官
Which, translated into world terms
轉換成世界性術語就是…
means a worldwide reduction of armaments
全世界的軍備縮減…
to such a point and in such a thorough fashion
要到達一個相當 徹底的水平
that no nation will be in a position
世界上沒有任何一個國家…
to commit an act of physical aggression
可以對其鄰國以及別的國
against any neighbor anywhere
發動任何性質的…
in the world.
軍事侵略
What the hell's the matter with him?
他到底在搞什麼？
He's asking us to trust our enemies, and he knows better.
他竟然讓我們 相信自己的敵人
You're absolutely right.
你說得沒錯
Hey, Laurel, you finished that very quickly.
嘿，勞拉，你做得可真快
Well, I hope so. Let's see, where were we? Uhh--
但願如此.我們來看看…
''And there''-- Oops. ''And therefore''-- Ah, here we are.
這一頁…對了，是這頁
''So if he does choose to support my program
「如果他選擇支持我的計劃」
let Senator Chapman be assured now
「能讓查普曼參議員知道…」
that I am fully aware of those qualities in him
我相信他優秀的個人能
which recommend him as cabinet material.''
「可成為競選 內閣議員的籌碼」
I think that says it exactly. You agree, Arthur?
說得很透徹，你說呢，亞瑟？
- Miss Scott, you should've been a diplomat. - I rather thought I was.
-斯科特小姐，你真應該去做外交官 -這我也想
Well, you certainly cooked up a compromise that's gonna make your boss
你剛幫自己的老闆 做了個業績宣言…
the next vice president of the United States.
這可助他當選下屆總統
I better type this up before you two start trying to improve on it.
我最好在你們改主意之前 把它給打出來
- Thanks, Laurel. - Here in downtown Honolulu
-謝了，勞拉 -這裡是壇香山
the weather is 78 under partly cloudy skies.
氣溫是78華氏度 部分地區多雲
Arthur, will you leave the girl enough clothes on not to catch cold?
亞瑟，你讓她穿那麼多衣服 是害怕她著涼嗎？
She's too valuable to me.
她可是我的無價之寶
Have you slept with her yet?
你跟她上過床了？
What kind of a question is that to ask a married man?
你怎麼能問一個 已婚男人這種問題？
- You son of a gun! - Think I better go check what she's doin'.
-你這個老混球！  -我去看看她做得怎麼樣了
- Oh, sure! - Arthur, have another drink
-好吧！  -亞瑟，再喝一杯吧
and stop thinking about how much everybody else is gettin'.
別老想著大家賺了多少錢
- Thanks! - See you later.
-謝了！  -一會兒見
We swung it, Laurel. How about that? We really swung it!
勞拉，我們快成功了. 怎麼樣？
- Did you tell him you were sleeping with me? - What?
-你跟他說你和我上過床了？ -什麼？
Laurel. I wish I was.
勞拉，我倒希望如此
- I'm not gonna lie about it. - People assume you are anyway.
-這種事我不會撒謊的 -大家都這樣懧為
- I'll just have to live with the fact. - Fact?
-看來我要和這事實共度此生了  -事實？
Of what they think.
人們的想法
You're a strange girl, Laurel.
你真是個奇怪的女孩 勞拉
You give more back talk and less cooperation than any girl on Capitol Hill.
你的嘴巴比國會裡 其他女孩都要厲害
I don't know why I put up with you and your dog.
真不知道自己為何能 忍受你和你這條狗
I don't know why I just don't fire you.
真不明白我為何不解雇你
Because I'm the best political assistant you'll find
因為我是最好的政客助手
and you're still more interested in politics than sex.
而且你對政治 比對性更感興趣
Charlie!
查理！
What is he barking at?
他在亂吠什麼？
Charlie, what is it?
查理，怎麼了？
Listen.
聽
They had U.S. markings.
上面還有美國標誌
- You sure of that? - I thought so too.
-你確定？ -我想是的
Their speed! Are they ours?
它們可真快.那是我們的？
I don't know. But if they are ours, they've kept them a close secret.
不知道.如果這是我們的 一定是他們向我們保密了
- I want inquiries made as soon as we return. - Yes, Senator.
-回去後趕緊去問一下 -好的，參議員先生
Bridge.
指揮塔
Skipper, the F-1 4s are on top of the contact.
艦長，F-14有情況要報告
Alert 1 , this is Eagle 1 . What have you got?
「警戒一號」，這是「鷹眼1號」 你有何發現？
We've overflown the craft, sir.
我們已經飛臨那艘船的上空
It's a civilian yacht, flying U.S. flag
那是艘遊艇，打著美國國旗
about 50 feet in length, old but in mint condition.
艦長約50英尺，式樣老舊
- Over. - Hold observation position.
-完畢 -繼續偵察
Dispatching 86 tanker for refueling.
已派86加油機前去加油
Stand clear, Path 1.
一號跑道準備完畢
86 tanker departing.
86號加油機出發
The challenger's back with one, two, threejabs to the mouth.
挑戰者被連續擊中三拳
Louis responds with a right to the head. Cuts with a left to the body.
路易斯頭部中了一記右勾拳. 身體中了一記左勾拳
- Brings it up to the head. - Hey, who's that fighting?
-頭部又中了一記 -誰在比賽呢？
- Louis takes another left and a right. - I don't know.
-路易斯又中一記左右勾拳 -我不知道
Louis is staggered by a right to thejaw. He almost goes down.
路易斯下巴吃了一記右勾拳. 他已經不支了
There's the bell ending round 1 2.
第12回合的終場鈴聲響了
Look sharp, feel sharp
「鋒利無比」
Be sharp and listen, mister How are you fixed for blades
「吹毛斷髮，這些刀片 你是怎麼做的？」
- Do you have plenty? - How are you fixed for blades
-你有很多嗎？ -這些刀片你是怎麼做的？
You're better off--
你最好是…
Let's get some air.
我們出去看看
Captain's off the Bridge.
艦長離開指揮塔
I don't know.
真搞不懂
Dan, what's this all about? What do you make of it?
丹，這到底怎麼回事？ 你對此有何想法？
Nostalgia broadcasting on the Armed Forces band.
軍事電台在播懷舊節目
Broadcasting after a strike? Nah.
被襲擊後還廣播？不
Excuse me.
對不起
Sir, is it possible that this could be part of some secret naval maneuver?
長官，這是不是海軍進行的 秘密演習？
- Course not. - There are a few people
-當然不是 -確實有不少人…
- who'd like to watch us work under pressure. - What are you saying, Dan?
-想看到我們忙得團團轉 -你在說什麼，丹？
The Department of Defense sent him out here.
國防部派他來這裡
Maybe they wanted to give him something to watch.
也許他們想演場好戲給他看
Now, that makes more sense than anything else so far.
目前看來，也就這說法 最有說服力
Now, wait a minute, gentlemen. You may be the victims of some kind of joke.
等一下，各位.你們也許 是某個玩笑的受害者
But whether the Pentagon's behind it
不管這玩笑背後 是五角大樓…
or the Kremlin or some little green men from Mars
克里姆林宮 或者火星上的外星人…
I promise you, I'm as much in the dark about it as you are.
但我保證，我和你們一樣 對此一無所知
Captain, we're getting something you might wanna hear.
艦長，有些東西你 也許想聽一下
- In the Plot Room. - Aye, sir.
-傳到策劃間去 -是，長官
The Germans are retreating on the 70-mile front in southern Russia.
在俄羅斯南線70英里 德軍正在撤退
However, forces were reported 200 miles from Moscow
但據報導，德軍距離莫斯科 只有兩百英里
and long-range artillery fire was heard in the suburbs of Moscow.
莫斯科市郊傳來陣陣 遠程大炮的炮擊聲
- Meanwhile in Washington-- - What the hell's going on here?
-與此同時，在華盛頓… -這到底怎麼回事？
Sir, I think you ought to see
長官，你來看看這個…
these aerial reconnaissance photographs of Pearl Harbor.
這些是從珍珠港 拍回來的偵察圖片
- Turn that off!. - Yes, sir.
-把那東西關掉！ -是，長官
That'll be all. You.
好了，沒你的事了
- It's not Pearl Harbor. - Sure as hell is.
-這不是珍珠港 -這確實是
Look at that old battle rig.
看那些老裝備
It's a memorial now. It's the Arizona.
它現在在博物館裡 這是「亞歷桑那號」
- But she's completely intact. - That's right.
-但她似乎完整無缺 -是的
- Get Mr. Lasky back up here. - Yes, sir.
-快讓萊斯基先生到 這兒拉絲-是，長官
What's the matter with you?
你怎麼了？
I was just on the Bridge. They're scared. Real scared.
我剛才在指揮塔. 他們很害怕
- What happened? - It's crazy.
-怎麼了？ -簡直瘋了
The Russians, us, even the Germans.
俄國人，我們，甚至德國人
- We've finally done it. - Done what, for Christ's sake?
-我們終於開干了 -開幹什麼？
- War. We're at war. - You always talkin' shit.
-戰爭，我們開戰了 -你總是胡扯
I want a straight answer
你實話跟我說
and I don't give a damn about any orders you've had elsewhere.
我才不管這是誰給你的命令
Is there something you've held back?
你有沒有隱瞞什麼？
Nothing. Absolutely nothing, Captain.
沒有.確實沒有，艦長
All right. I accept that.
好吧，我暫且相信
Here's a photo taken by our reconnaissance pilots less than an hour ago.
這是不到一小時前傳 回來的偵察圖片
- May I suggest something, Captain? - I'm wide open.
-我能給你點建議嗎 艦長？ -我洗耳恭聽
I suggest that you ask Commander Owens to come up here right away
我建議你讓歐文斯指揮官 帶著他那本書用到的圖片…
and bring the photos he's using to illustrate his book.
立刻趕到這兒來
Why?
為什麼？
I think he'll have something very interesting to show you.
也許有些東西你會很感興趣
All right.
好吧
Tanker, this is Alert 1. You got two thirsty Tomcats. Whaddya got?
加油機，這是「警戒一號」有兩架
I've got the hard stuff. Pull right in.
我有「美酒」，伸出管子
Contact.
連上了
We've got a green light.
綠燈顯示
Fill 'er up, check the oil and clean the windshield. Over.
加滿它.順便「擦」一下 郲風玻璃，完畢
Dick, where'd you get these?
迪克，這些是你從哪兒得來
I got them from the Smithsonian, sir. They're old agency photos of Pearl.
這是從「史密森尼博物館網站」
-Just like these. - Not like these.
-就像這些一樣 -不像這些
That one was taken less than an hour ago.
這照片是不到一小時前拍的
I don't understand, sir. These are pre-World War II pictures.
這不可能，長官.這些都是 二戰前拍的照片
This is the fleet that was destroyed.
這個艦隊已經被摧毀了
Sir, C.I.C. reports two bogeys at low altitude. Distance, 1 25 miles.
長官，雷達室報告發現兩架 低空飛行飛機.距離125英里
- Have our fighters take an I.D. pass. - Aye, Captain.
-派戰鬥機去證實對方身份 -是，艦長
Have our fighters investigate and identify the contact 090, signal Buster.
戰鬥機前去證實090區域 目標身份
Aye, sir. Alert 1 , this is Eagle Control.
是，長官.「警戒一號」 這裡是「飛鷹指揮塔」
Vector 2 1 0 for the bogeys. Bogeys low and slow.
目標航向210，低空慢速飛行
Your signal is Buster. I say again,your signal is Buster.
目標細小，重複，目標細小
Roger, Eagle Control. Alert 2 now completing its fueling.
明白，「飛鷹指揮塔」 「警戒二號」已加滿油
Vectoring 2 1 0. Out.
航向210，出發
That's the Arizona, Tennessee, West Virginia.
那是「亞歷桑那號」 「田納西號」，「西弗吉尼亞號」
You're saying
你是說…
that these are both photographs of Pearl Harbor
這兩張珍珠港的照片…
on December 6, 1 941 ?
是在1941年12月6號拍的？
Yes, sir.
是的
Our reconnaissance plane has just taken pictures
我們的偵察飛機 拍回的照片…
of something that hasn't existed
上面的東西消失了將近…
for over 40 years.
四十多年？
Sir, we've got I.D. on the bogeys.
長官，已證實目標飛機身份
- Captain's on the Bridge. - What button?
-艦長到 -號碼多少？
Eleven, sir.
十一，長官
Alert 1 , this is Eagle 1 . What have you got?
「警戒一號」，這裡是 「鷹眼一號」，你發現了什麼？
- TwoJapanese Zeros, sir. - Two what?
-兩架日本「零式」戰機 -兩架什麼？
Two trophy-class Mitsubishi A6Ms in original condition
兩架攜有三菱A6M機炮的 「零式」戰機
complete with all markings.
飛機上都有標誌
- I mean, they look brand new, sir. - Have you been spotted?
-它們看起來很新，長官 -你們被發現了嗎？
Negative. We're right on the side at 6.:00 high.
沒有.我們就在目標 上方6點鐘方向
Stay in visual contact. Take no action without clearance.
繼續監視，沒命令 不要輕舉妄動
Wilco, Eagle 1. Out.
明白，「鷹眼一號」.完畢
-Jack Benny and Rochester. - And newscasts from World War II.
-傑克.賓尼和羅切斯特 -二戰的廣播新聞
Somebody for some reason
有人出於某種意圖…
wants us to believe that we're back in 1 941 .
想讓我們以為自己 回到了1941年
- Now, who wants it? - The Russians.
-到底是誰？ -俄國人
- Oh, Dan. - Maybe. Power of psychology.
-噢，丹 -也許是心靈感應
Excuse me, Captain
對不起，艦長…
but we also have to consider one alternative possibility.
但我們還應該 想到另一種可能
What's that?
什麼可能？
The possibility that what's happening here is real.
所發生的這一切 都可能是真的
Geez, that's ridiculous.
簡直無稽之談
Maybe, but we have some pretty strong evidence, sir.
也許吧.但這些證據 都很有說服性
Let's not just write off one possible explanation for it
且不必找什麼理由來 解釋這種現象…
- because we don't happen to like it. - How would that be possible?
-我們也許是正好碰上了 -那種事怎麼可能呢？
- Could you explain that to me? - No, sir, I can't.
-你能解釋給我聽嗎？ -我無法解釋，長官
But all of us know that movement through time is possible.
但我們都知道，穿越時空 是有可能的
Einstein proved it.
愛因斯坦證明過
- In theory.
-理論上來說 -是的
So all we have to do is move through some storm at sea, and bingo--
就因為我們遇上了 一場風暴，因此…
we're all much more clever than Einstein.
我們都比愛因斯坦聰明了
What sort of storm was that, Commander? Certainly nothing like I've ever seen.
那是什麼樣的風暴，指揮官？ 我從沒見過那種現象
Nothing like any of us have ever seen.
我們都沒見過
There are forces in the universe
宇宙中有很多 不知名的力量…
which we're only now just beginning to understand.
我們現在才剛剛對 它們有所瞭解
I mean, understand through science, not superstition.
我是說通過科學來瞭解 並非通過迷信
There are black holes in space, antimatter, curved space--
宇宙中有黑洞，反物質 扭曲的空間…
things that are as strange to us
這些我們所陌生的東西…
as electricity would have been to people in the Middle Ages
正如同電流對中古時期 人們同樣陌生一樣
or this ship in World War II.
或者這艘回到 二戰時期的航母
Well, crew is anxious for an explanation too.
全體船員都想 知道事情究竟
Now, we've gotta get a clearer picture of all this.
我們要拿到 一張更清晰的照片
Let's go to C.I.C.
到雷達室去
Hey.
嘿
- What is it? - Listen.
-怎麼了？ -快聽
It's those planes again.
又是那些飛機
No, no. Different noise entirely.
不，這次的聲音不一樣
There they are.
它們在那兒
- They're not ours, are they? - No, certainly not.
-不是我們的飛機，對嗎？ -絕對不是
They haveJapanese markings.
上面有日本標誌
They're comin' in again.
它們又飛過來了
Laurel, ask the captain to radio Hawaii.
勞拉，讓船長 發信號給夏威夷
Find out aboutJapanese fighter planes in the area.
就說這裡發現日本戰鬥機
Yes, Senator.
是，議員先生
Oh, God! They're shooting!
噢，上帝！它們開槍了！
Oh, my God.
噢，上帝！
- Oh, no. - The captain send the message?
-噢，不 -船長髮信號了嗎？
We've gotta get off this boat.
我們快離開這艘船
Come on, Laurel!
快點，勞拉！
Eagle Control, this is Alert 1.
「飛鷹控制塔」 這裡是「警戒一號」
Theyjust strafed the hell out of that yacht.!
它們在向那艘遊艇開火！
Why would they attack a yacht?
它們為何要襲擊那艘遊艇？
Their job would be to destroy anything with a radio that could warn Pearl Harbor.
它們的任務是摧毀所有能 與珍珠港聯繫的無線電
Providing you and Mr. Einstein are correct.
你和愛因斯坦先生都說中了
Dick, where would theJapanese fleet be at this time on December 6, 1 941 ?
迪克，1941年12月6號的這時 候
Well, sir, they'd be off the scope
長官，這應該在雷達範圍
but an educated guess would be around about here.
但它們很可能就在這裡附近
Excuse me. They'd have to be here, up around the northwest sector.
對不起.它們應該就在這裡 西北海域附近
Let's get this settled once and for all. Have the E-2 check it out.
立即派E-2偵察機前 去那裡證實
I wanna see if theJapanese task force is out there.
我想知道，那裡 是否有日本艦隊
Yes, sir.
是，長官
Eagle Control, Alert 1. They're making another run.
「飛鷹控制塔」，這裡是 「警戒一號」，它們又返回了
Jesus.! They'll shoot that damn yacht to pieces.!
上帝！它們想摧毀那艘遊艇！
Request permission to arm and fire.
請求開火射擊！
- For God sakes, Skipper-- - Negative.
-艦長…  -不行
- Charlie? Charlie! - No, Laurel! Not now!
-查理！  -不，勞拉！還不行！
Come on! Those planes are coming in! Come on!
快！那些飛機快來了！快點！
Let's go! Come on, Harvey!
走啊，快，哈維！
Eagle Control, they blew it to bits. They must've hit the fuel tank.!
「飛鷹控制塔」，小艇 在敵機炮轟中爆炸 應該是被擊中了燃料槽
- Any survivors? - Stand by.
-有無人生存？ -正在觀察
Affiirmative. One, two, three Mae Wests.!
確定，1，2，3，有 三人穿著救生背心！
Hey, wait a minute! Those bastards are turning back!
等等！那些混蛋又折回了！
They're gonna strafe them in the water! Request permission to fire.
要射殺水中的倖存者！ 請求准許開火！
This is Eagle 1 . You are cleared to arm, but do not fire.
這裡是「鷹眼一號」 允許裝備彈藥，但勿開火
Throw them off, play with them, but don't fire.
跟他們玩捉迷藏 架就別打了
Affirmative.
遵命
- Sam! Sam. - All right. It's all right. I'm all right.
-山姆！山姆 -沒事，沒事，我很好
Look up!
看上面！
Oh, no! They're coming again!
怎麼又來了！
Harvey! Get that life preserver off and dive!
哈維！脫下救生衣，潛下水面！
I can't swim!
我不會游泳！
Here they come!
他們來了！
He's dead.
他死了
It's okay. Easy, boy. Up you go.
不要緊，乖狗狗，慢點，上去
Hey, Fox, that woke 'em up!
福克斯，這招讓 他們如夢初醒啊！
I think we should give 'em another shot.
再嚇嚇他們
Why the hell are we playing with these guys?
跟這些人玩個啥勁？
Radar shows enemy planes heading on course, 220.
雷達顯示敵機 正按軌道行進，220
- 220. - SweetJesus.
-220 -這可不妙
Skipper, they're headed straight for us
艦長，敵人可是 直來燎我們虎鬚
and we've got an armed strike force just sitting on the deck.
而我們甲板上 有整隊武裝打擊力量
Alert 1 , this is Eagle 1 . You're cleared to fire.
「警戒一號」，這裡是 「鷹眼一號」，允許開火
Splash the Zeros. I say again, splash the Zeros.
殲滅這兩架零式戰機 重複，殲滅零式戰機
- Yes, sir. - This has gotta be a dream.
-是，長官 -希望真是一場夢幻
Eagle Control, Alert 1.
「飛鷹控制塔」 這裡是「警戒一號」
Splash two. Repeat.
殲滅兩架敵機，重複
Splash two.
殲滅兩架敵機
Possibly one survivor in the water.
其中一名駕駛員 可能跳至水面，仍然在生
Captain, the E-2 is coming upon Point Charlie.
艦長，E-2正前 去落水地點
Eagle Control, we have multiple radar contacts
「飛鷹控制塔」 456方向接收到…
picking up on 456 heading.
大量雷達通訊
Possible carriers and 2 4 escort ships.
也許是航空母艦 以及24艘護衛艦
Southeasterly heading.
東南航向
Negative radio or radar emissions.
探測不到無線電 或雷達發射
Request instructions. Over.
請求指示，完畢
That is theJapanese attack force.
是日軍打擊力量
Yeah. I guess now we know.
是，我們算是確證了
Look, Dick. Take personal charge of a rescue team
迪克，你領 一支救援部隊
and keep the survivors isolated.
敵我生還者要隔離開
- Crazy situation. - Yes, sir.
-這形勢簡直荒謬 -遵命，長官
- You know what I want. - I understand.
-你知我意欲何為的 -明白
Keep the fighters airborne to cover the rescue.
保證空中有戰機掩護救援
Aye, aye, Skipper.
遵命，艦長
Now track and report all movements of theJapanese task force.
跟蹤報告所有 日軍特遣隊的行動
- Aye, aye, sir. - Do you still think it's a dream?
-遵命，長官 -還懧為這不過是個夢麼？
It's a nightmare.
成夢靨了
Let go! Forget the damn dog!
放手！別管狗了！
- Boss, 36. - Go ahead, 36.
-艦長，我是36 -36，報告
We got two survivors and now we're waiting to pick up Kag.
救上兩名生還者 正等著接應凱格
- Kag? What the hell is he doing in the water? - Damned if I know.
-凱格？他還在水下幹嘛？ -天知道
Charlie!
查理！
You all right, ma'am?
沒事吧，女士？
How you feeling, sir?
感覺還好麼，先生？
What the hell kind of machine is this thing? And what's your ship, Commander?
你們這是什麼東西？ 指揮官，你什麼艦隊的？
It's an aircraft carrier, sir. I'm Air Wing Commander Richard Owens.
我們率屬航空母艦，我是空軍 部隊指揮官理查德.歐文斯斯
- Sam Chapman. - Senator Samuel Chapman?
-我是塞繆爾.查普曼 -塞繆爾.查普曼參議員？
That's right.
沒錯
Sure am glad you were out here.
有你們在真感幸運
Yes, sir.
是
Okay, Senator, watch yourself.
參議員，小心
Watch your head.
看頭
- All right, take it easy. - Hang on to me, sir.
-慢著來 -靠著我
You'll be just fine.
你不會有事
It's all right, ma'am. Go with him.
沒關係，女士，你跟他去吧
I'll take the dog, Commander.
指揮官，狗我來拿吧
Little bastard.
小雜碎
Corporal!
下士！
Mind the store, Ray. I'm going forward.
雷，盯緊屏幕，我到前面去
- Holy cow. - It's the wholeJapanese fleet.
-見鬼了  -全都是日本艦隊
Have these things returned to theJapanese pilot. Get this translated.
將這些都還給那日本飛行員 這個拿去翻譯
Captain's on the Bridge.
艦長登艙
Mr. Lasky. Gentlemen.
萊斯基先生，各位
Captain's off the Bridge.
艦長離艙
We can't ignore it any longer.
不能再置身事外了
Every man on this ship knows that we have radar and visual contact
艦上各人都知道，無論 雷達還是偵察員親眼眼見
with a Japanese fleet approaching Pearl Harbor
都顯示有一隊日本艦隊 接近珍珠港
on December 6, 1 941 .
正是在1941年12月6日當天
- Now, what do we do about it? - Skipper,
-我們該如何？ -艦長
what we do about it is blow them out of the water.
我懧為該做的 就是把這些肉碎轟上天
The U.S.S. Nimitz declares war on theJapanese empire?
尼米茲號對日本帝國宣戰？
That's what we'd be doing. But they haven't attacked Pearl Harbor yet.
若我們這麼做就是這個後果 但他們可還沒進攻珍珠港啊
The only evidence we have that they intend to is in the history books.
能證明他們有意進攻 也僅是我們在歷史書裡所得
It opens up some amazing possibilities.
這樣的話也許會帶來 數種令人驚詫的可能性
Think of the firepower of the U.S.S. Nimitz back in 1 941 .
試想想1941年能 有尼米茲號的打擊力量
What kind of possibilities, Mr. Lasky?
萊斯基先生，能有 什麼可能性？
Possibilities for the future, Mr. Owens.
改變未來的可能性 歐文斯斯先生
Think of the history of the next 40 years.
為接下來40年的 歷史考慮一下
I have a suspicion history will be a little more difficult to beat
萊斯基先生，我強烈置 疑歷史會能比你想像的
than you imagine, Mr. Lasky.
有多大改變
I'm talking about the classic paradox of time.
我說的是關於時間的 經典矛盾論
Imagine, for example, I go back in time to meet my own grandfather
舉例吧，想像一下我 回到過去，見到我的祖父
long before he got married, before he had children.
而其時他根本還沒結婚 也沒孩子
We have an argument, and I kill him.
我們發生了爭吵 我殺了他
Now, if that happens, how am I ever gonna be born?
若確實發生這樣的事 我怎麼可能還生得出來呢？
And if I can never be born, how can I go back in history
那若是我生不出來，我又怎 可能返回自己原先的歷史
and meet my very own grandfather?
去見我祖父？
I'm not half the theorist you are, Mr. Lasky
萊斯基先生 我沒你那麼多理論
but I still have a gut instinct that things only happen once.
我只是本能覺得 事情僅可能發生一次
And if they have happened, then there's nothing we can do to change them
而要是發生了 我們便改變不得
- nor should we try. - How are you gonna avoid it?
-也不該嘗試改變 -但怎麼去避免？
It's already happening, and we're already involved.
事情正在發生 而我們都置身事內
For Christ's sake, what is this? Some half-ass Princeton debating society?
好了好了，這算什麼？ 普林斯頓辯論會嗎？
We are in a war situation.
現在我們直面戰爭
This is a United States warship
這是美國戰艦
or at least it used to be.
至少曾是
Or will be. Or what the hell ever.
或將是，隨便怎樣
Oh, goddamn it, you can drive yourself crazy
見鬼，這個問題光是想想
trying to think about this stuff.
就能把人給整瘋了
-Jesus, I must be dreaming! - Now, hold it.
-天，我一定是在作夢！ -暫且打住
All right. Let's all calm down.
我們都冷靜一點
Let's take it one step at a time and by the book.
我們且以歷史書按部就班
If the United States of America falls under attack
若是美國受到了襲擊
our job is to defend her
我們的任務 就是保衛祖國
in the past, present or future.
無論是過去 現在，抑或將來
- And after that? - After that, we take our orders
-那之後呢？ -之後，我們便受命…
from the commander in chief of the United States Armed Forces.
美國空軍主將
Franklin Delano Roosevelt?
羅斯福？
- Everything all right here? - You in command of this ship?
-這裡一切還好吧？ -你負責這首航母？
Oh, hardly. No, I'm a doctor. Ship's commander is Captain Yelland.
那可要我老命，我是醫生 航母司令官是耶蘭德艦長
I'm sure he'll be down to see you as soon as possible.
我看他一會便會來見您的了
- I certainly hope so. - Meanwhile, you both seem
-這就好 -不過你倆…
- none the worse for your little mishap. - Mishap?
-在這段小災也算好運 -小災？
You call getting a boat shot out from under you
一艘小艇在你面前被擊沉
and three people dead a mishap?
死了三人，這叫小災？
- Are we at war? Is that what happened? - I'm not in a position to--
-我們是開戰了還是怎麼？ -以我的地位我…
Am I glad to see you.
見到你可真開心
Doctor
醫生
would you please inform the captain that Senator Samuel Chapman
請知會艦長 塞繆爾.查普曼參議員
cochairman of the Senate Defense Committee
參議院國防委員會副主席
would like to see him at once?
要求馬上會面
Of course, Senator.
沒問題，參議員
Doctor, I believe I said at once.
醫生，我說了是馬上！
First, a vitamin shot. Now, if you'll both roll up your sleeves.
先來打針維生素 請兩位捲起袖子
- Senator. - No, goddamn it!
-參議員  -見鬼！
Now, you can take up your needles, Doctor
你趕快拿上針筒
and whatever's in them and get the hell out of here!
還有裡面的什麼藥滾出去
Corporal?
下士？
What the hell are we, prisoners?
我們現在算是什麼，囚犯？
Holy shit.
糟
Smoking lamp is lighted in all authorized spaces.
所有指定區域已亮起導航燈
Son of a--
他媽…
So, history may be tougher to beat than I imagined.
看來歷史比我 想像的要難改變
You're becoming a real pain in the ass, Lasky.
萊斯基，你越來 越令人頭疼了
You take an awful lot of risks for someone who's supposed to be intelligent.
做事放聰明點 你犯的險夠多了
Do I? ''The attack on Pearl Harbor was far from a surprise for many people
是嗎？「日軍對珍珠港的襲擊 出乎許多人意料之外」
among them, the prominent and ambitious Samuel S. Chapman
「其中便有知名熱望的 塞繆爾參議員」
who had only two weeks before
「僅在兩周前」
publicly argued for an increase in our strength in the Pacific.
「他才公然爭辯要加強 對太平洋的防禦」
Ironically, the senator disappeared and was presumed dead
「諷刺的是，參議員卻在 自己清楚預見的襲擊之後」
following the attack he had foreseen so clearly.
「離奇失蹤，並被假設死亡」
Had he lived, it's very possible
「若他在生，查普曼大有可能」
Chapman could have been Roosevelt's running mate in the 1 944 election
「成為羅斯福1944年 競選時的競選夥伴」
and upon his death, the next president of the United States.''
「並在羅斯福身後 繼任美國總統」
Now if that doesn't come under the heading of trying to beat history
你若說這還不叫 擾亂歷史陣腳
I don't know what does.
那我真不知道什麼才算了
Lasky, I realized who we had the moment I heard his name.
萊斯基，我聽到他名字 便知道救上來的是什麼人
Why'd you keep it to yourself?
那你為何不說？
I don't have your appetite for playing God with the world.
我沒你拿上帝跟世界 開玩笑那種愛好
What was I supposed to do, throw him back in the sea?
我能怎麼辦？難道 又把他澤下海？
At least that would have preserved
若是這樣，起碼也算
the natural order of history as you've written it.
保護了已寫下的歷史的 自然順序
Go to hell, Lasky.
你去死吧，萊斯基
Go to hell yourself. I wanna meet Chapman.
你才去死，我要見查普曼
Goddamn it.
見鬼
If this wasn't happening to me, I wouldn't believe it.
要不是事情確實發生在 我身上了，我真是不敢相信
- Who the hell are these people? - The navy.
-這些都是什麼人啊？ -海軍啊
Yeah, the navy, yeah. But what part of it?
對，海軍，沒錯，可是 是海軍哪部分？
I've never seen machines like they got onboard this thing.
他們艦上那些飛機 我從沒見過
And where have they been developing aircraft like that?
它們是從何研究 發展出來的？
The navy would have to appear before my committee
海軍起碼該給我的 委員會通傳的嘛
and I've never even heard a whisper about it.
但這一點風聲都沒有
Rocket planes and that thing they pulled us out of the sea with.
對那些攜帶導彈的飛機 和將我們救出水面的 飛行器我們一無所知
And naming this ship after Chester Nimitz, an active-duty admiral.
還將這艘艦以切斯特.尼米茲 一個現任元帥的大姓來命名
What the hell's going on here?
這到底都怎麼了？
Yeah, Roosevelt. He owns the military.
對了，羅斯福，軍隊歸他管
That's it.
沒錯了
That's exactly who.
一定就是他
F.D.R. has wanted the United States in this war since it started
羅斯福一開始便想美國參戰
but he knows there's no way it's gonna happen
但他也知道這不可能
except in response to an attack.
除非是我國受襲進行反擊
- You always said theJapanese would attack. - That's right.
-但你一直都說日本會 襲擊我國的啊-沒錯
And who's sitting out here with no press
但拉響了警報，作好了 反擊準備這份功勞
while the White House takes all the credit for raising the alarm
卻全都歸到了白宮頭上
and being ready to hit back?
卻是誰坐在此地 身無鎂光相伴呢？
- Obviously, we are. - Goddamn it!
-很顯然是我們 -靠！
Anything?
有何收穫？
Whoever he is, he's either too scared
他是什麼身份都好 說的東西都因惶惶不安
or too well briefed to talk about it.
或語無倫次說得模棱兩可
Excuse me.
失陪
All right, Corporal.
下士
Commander, I demand to know why we're being held prisoners.
指揮官，我要求解釋為 何以囚犯待遇相待我們
Here wait. I got him.
等等，我來幫你抓
Jesus Christ!
老天！
No, don't!
不要！
Oh, my God.
天啊
The prisoner has shot one, maybe two of your men.
俘虜射殺了你一名手下 也許倆
Move in!
前進！
Captain, prisoner grabbed a weapon.
艦長，俘虜搶得武器
He shot one of my men, maybe two.
槍殺了我一名或兩名軍士
We're in position. The area is sealed off.
我們已到位，該區已然封鎖
Stand by.
待命
Get Lieutenant Kajima up here on the double.
叫鹿島上尉趕快來此
Can't we get a translator down here, for God's sakes?
拜託，能不能找個翻譯啊？
How the hell do we know what he's saying if we can't understand him?
我們聽不懂怎麼 知道他要什麼？
We need a translator to tell him we need a translator.
我們需要翻譯 告訴他我們需要翻譯
Maybe that's just what he's trying to tell us.
也許他也正這麼說
All right, Dick, Lieutenant Kajima is here. Put it on the box.
迪克，鹿島上尉已到 揚聲器通話
Ask him what he wants.
問他要什麼
He wants access to a radio, sir.
他要用無線電，長官
Does he say why?
說了原因沒有？
Because he wants to warn his commander
因為他要給自己的 指揮官預警
about us.
我們的存在
He repeats the demand.
他重複了一遍要求
- Or else? - He will kill again.
-否則？ -再開殺戒
Do you think there's a chance they might believe him?
你看有否機會他們 會相信他的話？
There's no chance if things remain the way they are.
事情若無改變 那什麼機會都無
Tell him we agree.
跟他說我們同意
- You son of a-- - No! Don't shoot! Back off!.
-你這… -不！別開火！退後！
Don't shoot!
別開槍！
Back off!. Back off!.
後退！後退！別開槍！
What the hell's going on down there?
那邊怎麼回事？
He says one more attempt to trick him and the girl is dead.
他說，若再企圖設陷 他就殺了那女的
There'll be no tricks. He can use the radio room if he frees the girl.
我們不會再有陷阱，他放了 那女孩便可使用無線電
Says he doesn't believe you.
他說不相信你
Why don't you tell him what's going on here, Commander?
指揮官，你乾脆將 即將發生的一切告訴他好了
You're an expert on what's gonna happen tomorrow
對明天的事你是專家
tell him about it, for God's sakes.
跟他說了吧，拜託
Go on, tell him! We got nothing to lose!
說吧！反正我們無可損失！
Go ahead, tell him.
你說吧
26 November, six carriers left the Coral Isles north ofJapan.
11月26日，六艘航母 駛離日本北部珊瑚島
The carriers were the Akagi, Kaga, Shokaku
六艘航母分別是赤城號 加賀號，翔鶴號
Zuikaku, Hiryu, Soryu.
瑞鶴號，飛龍號，蒼龍號
Tomorrow at dawn, these carriers will send 3 53 planes
明日黎明，這幾艘航母 將派出353輛戰機
to attack Pearl Harbor.
進攻珍珠港
How in the hell do you know all that?
你怎麼知道這些的？
Your code is ''Climb Mount Niitaka.''
你們的指令代碼是 「登上新高梨峰」
What's going on?
到底怎麼回事？
Please, Miss Scott, don't ask me any questions.
斯科特小姐 請別問我任何問題
There isn't anything I can tell you at this time.
我現在什麼都還不能說
All right?
好不好？
Where's Charlie? Where's my dog?
查理呢？我的狗哪去了？
We'll find him, Miss Scott.
我們找得到它的 斯科特小姐
He can't get off the ship.
它又不懂得下船
Casualties will be moved down to secondary triage.
傷亡人員按傷重程度 二級分類治療
I wanna get out of this bathrobe and into some clothes!
我不要再穿這見鬼的浴袍 給我找幾件衣服
Will somebody please get me some clothes? For God's sakes!
來人幫我找幾件 衣服好嗎？拜託
- Chief, get the senator some clothes. - Yes, sir.
-輪機長，去給參議員找些衣服 -是
Senator, Matt Yelland, commanding officer.
參議員，我是 馬特.耶蘭德，該艦艇指揮官
Where and how did you get all this information I've been hearing?
我剛才聽到的那些信息 你是從哪，以何途徑獲得的？
- And is it true? - Yes, sir.
-另外是否屬實？ -確實
Did you inform Pearl Harbor Command?
那你通知了珍珠港 指揮部沒有？
- No, Senator. - Why the hell not?
-沒有，參議員 -為何不通知？
Well, the reasons are a little complicated, but, uh, believe me, Senator
原因比較複雜，不過… 請相信我，參議員
this carrier is capable of handling any attack should it occur.
這艘戰艦應付任何可能 發生的襲擊都絕無問題
One carrier against a whole fleet?
一艘航母對抗整只艦隊？
What kind of an idiot do you take me for?
你把我當哪類白癡啊？
- Senator, calm down. - The hell with you.
-參議員，冷靜下來 -冷靜你個頭
Tell Pearl Harbor what's happening here, or I'll talk to them.
趕快通知珍珠港這裡的 情況，不然就我來
Very well.
很好
Dan, set up the communications in my inport cabin.
丹，準備通信設備
Wouldn't you like to talk to them with some clothes on?
先穿上衣服 再跟他們談好嗎？
- Thank you, Captain. - Follow me, sir.
-謝謝，艦長 -請隨我來，長官
- Are you all right? - Yes, sir, I'm fine.
-沒事吧？ -我沒什麼
Can you do that, Captain?
艦長，能行嗎？
Contact Pearl Harbor back in 1 941 .
跟1941年的 珍珠港聯絡
I think so.
我想行吧
- Then what do you do? - One step at a time.
-那然後怎辦？ -按部就班
Yeah. Like a minefield.
對，像我們身處佈雷區
This is, uh, Senator Samuel S. Chapman of the United States Senate
我是美國參議院參議員 塞繆爾.查普曼
onboard the aircraft carrier Nimitz.
我現在尼米茲號航空母艦
Captain Yelland is here with me.
耶蘭德艦長與我一起
- You're on what? - I repeat.
-你在哪艘艦上？ -重複
I am Senator Samuel S. Chapman onboard the U.S.S. Nimitz.
我是塞繆爾參議員 現在尼米茲號航母上
All right, whoever the hell you are
我管你是誰
use of military frequencies by unauthorized personnel is a felony.
未經授權使用軍方 頻率可是嚴重罪行
Now just a minute here, sir.
長官，你先稍等
As we have no aircraft carrier Nimitz and no Captain Yelland
我們並無任何航母號 「尼米茲」，也沒有 什麼耶蘭德艦長
I suggest, asshole, that you stop impersonating some other asshole
傻冒，別再冒充別人
and get off the air.
也別再使用無線電
You're wasting our time.
你在浪費我們時間
How dare you talk to me that way! Captain, tell him who you are.
你怎可如此語氣與我說話！ 艦長，跟他說明你的身份
Speak to them!
跟他們說啊！
You, what are you doing here? You're a civilian.
你，你怎麼上來的？ 你不過是文官
Yes, sir, I'm with the Department of Def--
對，我是國防部…
I mean, the Navy Department.
我是指海軍軍部
That's more like it. What's going on here?
這才像樣，這裡到底 怎麼回事？
I'm afraid I'm just an observer here, sir.
我只是旁觀者
I couldn't tell you anything more than you already know.
恐怕就不能透露比你 目前所知更多的情況了
What's happening here?
這裡到底怎麼回事？
Who are you people?
你們到底是什麼人？
-join him in his inport cabin. - Thank you.
-到通信艙見他 -謝謝
I'll wait outside while you change.
你換衣我到外面等
Please, I really don't want to be left alone right now.
我現在真不想 被一個人留下
I'll just be a minute.
很快
Just exactly what is it you do for the senator, Miss Scott?
斯科特小姐，您確切說 來是為參議員幹些什麼的呢？
I work for him, Commander.
指揮官，我為他幹事
I'd like to think I'm more than just a secretary.
但我看自己也不單純 只是個秘書
I write most of his speeches, and in general, I'm his assistant.
他大多數演講稿都是我下筆 大體說來，我是他助手的角色
It's quite an accomplishment for a woman in your day--
你一個女人如此也算成就 這個年代…
this day and age.
這個年歲
Let me tell you something. I'm ambitious and very capable.
我實話跟你說，我 也有鴻圖大志，能力十足
That's a combination that's not much appreciated.
這樣的結合卻不令人賞識
It's a man's world. I'm sure you'll agree.
畢竟這是男人的世界啊 相信你也會贊同我的說法
It certainly is, Miss Scott.
這是確實，斯科特小姐
I spent a lot of time trying to hide the way I look
我常常掩飾自己的容顏
hoping to be recognized for my ability.
希望更多是被 懧同自己的能力
- How's it going so far? - Well, let me put it this way.
-那結果如何？ -我這麼說吧
If the way I look gets me in the door, then God help them when I get through.
若是容顏的關係領 我進了門，那恐怕由始至終 都要靠之襄助了
You're a remarkable woman, Miss Scott.
斯科特小姐 您真是位不平常的女性
Shall we?
該走了麼？
Yeah.
好
Enemy fleet bears 042 degrees.
敵軍艦隊轉向042角度
Captain, they bear 042 degrees
艦長，敵人轉向042角度
range 1 82 miles, course 1 80, speed 1 2.
範圍182英里 航向180，速度12節
Very well. Keep me advised.
很好，隨時通傳
35 degrees, 1 7 miles north, northwest of Pearl.
35度角，北面17英里 珍珠港西北方
Laurel, are you all right?
勞拉，你沒事吧？
Miss Scott, I'm Matt Yelland, skipper of this ship.
斯科特小姐，我是 馬特.耶蘭德，該航母艦長
Thank you for your hospitality, Captain
艦長，謝謝您的款待
but I insist you fly Miss Scott and myself
但我堅持您派出飛機 載我與斯科特小姐
to Pearl Harbor immediately.
立即飛往珍珠港
- Very well. Lieutenant. - Yes, sir.
-好.上尉 -是，長官
Follow this officer. He'll see that you're fully equipped
你們跟著這位長官 他會帶你們裝備
and then escort you to the hangar deck.
然後送你們到戰機甲板
Thank you, Captain.
謝謝，艦長
- Charlie? - Forget about the dog. He'll be all right.
-查理？ -別管狗了 他不會有事
Wait a minute, Captain. I think you're making a big mistake here.
等等，艦長，我看你 這麼做是犯大錯
That man mysteriously disappeared on December 7, 1 941 . That's today, sir.
那人1941年12月7日 神秘失蹤，也就是今天
Now, at the present time, he is the front-running candidate
目前他可是民主黨人1944年
for the vice presidential spot on the Democratic ticket in 1 944.
競選副總統的熱門人選
And if he survives, he's almost certain
他要是活著 他將來那是必定
to become the president of the United States
會在羅斯福1945年 四月逝世之後
when Roosevelt dies in April of 1 945.
成為美國總統的
Sir, don't you think he'd be a whole lot safer to stay on the ship for the time being?
您難道不覺得讓他先呆在 艦上會更安全嗎，長官？
Mr. Lasky, my job is to make decisions here, now
萊斯基先生，我的職責是對 這艘航母上的一切作出決定
not worry about what politician may be in the White House
而不是關心何種政客 將會入主白宮…
- four years from now or 40 years ago. - But, sir--
-無論是這之後四年，或是換言之40年前 -可是長
And right now, I don't like having two civilians on my ship
我現在不想在即將開戰之際
when I'm about to do battle.
在艦上多出兩名文官
You've got three civilians.
那你該是有三名
Mr. Lasky, you're free to go with them if you like.
萊斯基先生，你要喜歡 也可以跟他們一起走
Dick.
迪克
Just got enough time to drop them off on a deserted spot on this island.
你有足夠時間載他們 至這個島嶼的荒廢據點
Not Pearl, sir?
不是珍珠港嗎？
Hell, no. They'll be a whole lot safer there.
才怪，在這會比較安全
We'll equip them to look after themselves till it's over.
我會給他們足夠裝備 照料自己，等到戰事結束
I'll feel a lot easier with them off my hands.
他們不在我會感到輕鬆些
Yes, sir.
是，長官
Be sure you're back by 07 00.
7點前一定要回來
I want my best man commanding that strike force.
我要自己的最精英 指揮這場戰事
Yes, sir.
是，長官
Now hear this.
請注意，請注意
All hands, stand by
所有人員待命
for special announcement from the captain in 1 5 minutes.
船長15分鐘後有特別通知
What are you doing here, Mr. Lasky?
萊斯基先生，你在這幹嗎？
I wanna go to Pearl Harbor with you.
我要跟你去珍珠港
Wait a minute. You're not going to Pearl, are you?
等等，你目的地不是珍珠港？
Do they know?
他們知道不？
Captain, enemy fleet 1 7 0 miles north, northwest Pearl.
艦長，敵軍艦隊在北面 170英里，珍珠港西北面
TheJapanese fleet now bears 055 degrees, 1 62 miles.
日軍艦隊轉向055角度 162英里
Look at all this ordnance.
看這些軍火
Yeah, it's gotta be the real thing.
是啊，可要用上了
Watch that wing tip!
小心機翼！
This is the captain.
我是艦長
I'm speaking to every man aboard this ship.
請艦上所有人員注意
In the past few hours, many things have happened
過去數小時內發生了 許多事情
but rumors of nuclear attacks
但一切關於核攻擊
and a third world war are totally untrue.
或第三次世界大戰的 謠言都是不實的
We have no reason to believe that any aggression has been taken
我們並無理由相信有任何 對我們家園和家人的襲擊
against our homes and families.
正在進行
I believe that what we have stumbled across is not man-made
我相信這次的迷惘並非人為
but a phenomena of nature.
而是自然現象
One that can't be explained.
無法解釋的自然現象
Now, this phenomena is a storm which the Nimitz went through
這種現象就是尼米茲號 不足18小時前
less than 1 8 hours ago.
經歷的那風暴
This storm has had some effect on time as we know it.
這場風暴就目前我們所知 對時間產生了某種效應
It created a portal, a door into another era.
造成了進入 另一個時代的入口
Today is December 7, 1 94 1.
今天其實是1941年12月7日
I'm sure we're all aware of the significance of this date
我相信各位都很清楚 這個日子的意義
and its place in history.
以及在歷史中的地位
We're about to fight a battle that was lost
我們即將展開一場，在 你們大多數人還未出生前
before most of you were born.
便已輸掉的戰爭
This time, with God's help
但在鬼使神差之下
it's going to be different.
歷史有可能改寫
Good luck.
祝福各位好運
Hey, Charlie.
查理
Good boy. Where you been hiding?
乖狗狗，你藏哪兒去了？
You wanna come with me? Come on, boy.
跟我來麼？來，狗狗
Eagle Control, 736.
「飛鷹控制塔」，這裡是736
E. T.A. destination three minutes.
預計抵達目的地時間，3分鐘
All right, let's move it!
下來吧！
This isn't Pearl Harbor!
這裡不是珍珠港！
Following orders, Commander?
指揮官，你這叫聽命令？
That's right, Senator.
沒錯，參議員
Is Commander Owens in the air yet?
歐文斯斯指揮官 聯繫上了嗎？
- No, sir. - Let me know the moment he's airborne.
-還未，長官 -一聯絡上便通知我
Yes, sir.
是
Why didn't you go with them?
怎麼不跟他們走？
I wasn't invited.
我未受邀請
Skipper, it's time to go.
艦長，該走了
Then let's go... to Pearl Harbor.
那就走吧…去珍珠港
You shoot that in here, we're all going up.
你開這槍，我們全完蛋
Then you better do what I say. Take off. Now!
那就照我說的做 起飛，馬上！
Don't let it go off!.
別讓他開著槍！
- I lost it. I lost the helo! - What?
-沒了信號，直升機信號沒了！  -什麼？
I tell you, I lost it. It just disappeared from the scope.
我說沒了信號，它在 觀測儀上消失了
What the hell do you mean it just disappeared?
你說消失了什麼意思？
That's it, Captain.
艦長，就是…
One second it was on the scope, the next it was gone.
之前一秒觀測儀上 還有蹤跡，接下就消失了
Search party?
要派人搜尋嗎？
It's too late. Officer of the deck, turn the Nimitz into the wind.
太遲了，甲板指揮 尼米茲空中戰機出發
Aye, aye, Captain.
是，艦長
- Launch aircraft. - Yes, sir, Captain.
-戰機出發 -是，長官
That's it. Let's go. Cats, you got green lights. Get 'em in the air!
好，出發，「雄貓」們 可以起飛，上空吧！
Victory 2 1 0, this is Zulu-5-Bravo.
勝利210，這裡是祖魯-5-B
Your vector 1 20. Estimated time of intercept 07 40. Over.
你航向120處，預計 截擊時間0740，完畢
Zulu-5-Bravo, this is Victory 2 1 0.
祖魯-5-B，這裡是勝利210
Nine minutes to intercept.
尚有九分鐘截擊
Sir, I think you oughta see this.
長官，您過來看看
It suddenly appeared behind us.
突然出現在我們後方
I don't believe this. It's starting again.
難以置信，又來了
Do you think we can outrun it?
我們能否逃過？
Maybe we oughta be asking ourselves should we even be trying to outrun it.
也許該問問自己，我們是否要
Six minutes to intercept.
六分鐘截擊
Change course to 1 80.
更換航道至180
- All ahead, flank speed. - Steady course 1 80.
-以極高速度前進 -固定航道180
- Come to course 1 80, aye, sir. - All ahead flank.
-轉向航道180，遵命 -極高速前進
- Indicate 1 25 R.P.M. - All ahead flank, indicate 1 25 R.P.M.
-渦輪轉速增至125轉/分 -極高速前進，渦輪轉速增至125轉/分
Zulu-5-Bravo, this is Victory 2 1 0.
祖魯-5-B，這裡是勝利210
I have enemy bandits on radar. Approximately four minutes to intercept.
敵機蹤跡已在雷達顯示 約4分鐘後截擊
2 1 0, this is Zulu-5-Bravo. You're cleared to arm.
210，這裡是祖魯-5-B 准許武裝
Sir, when we changed course, the storm changed course.
長官，我們更換航道 風暴也更換航道
It's following us and growing at the same time.
它同時跟隨膨脹
I'm recalling those planes.
召回戰機
- Wait a minute, sir. You can't do that. - What are you talking about?
-等等，長官，你不可如此 -你說什麼？
We've got an incredible opportunity here.
我們這是千載難逢之機
We know where all the mistakes are gonna be made for the next 40 years
接下去40年美國犯過的 錯誤我們都知曉
and you've got the power to correct them.
而你有足夠的力量去更正
You stay out of this.
你別管這事
Scrub the mission. Get those planes back.
任務取消，召回戰機
Your signal is Buster. I say again, your signal is Buster.
以最大巡航速度飛行 重複，最大巡航速度飛行
Read you loud and clear.
清楚明白
Strike Force, this is Strike Leader.
空中力量，我是領機
Return to base. Mission aborted.
返回基地，任務撤銷
Mission aborted? But we can see 'em?
任務撤銷？可是我們 都看得見他們了？
Shit, they're gonna let theJaps do it again.
媽的，又讓小日本再干了 一回齷齪事
This is the captain. Now hear this, men.
我是艦長，各位請注意
We've been through it once, we're going through it again.
我們又要再經歷一次風暴
Prepare for approaching storm.
作好接近準備
We interrupt this program to bring you a special news bulletin.
我們暫且中斷節目 為各位帶來一則特別新聞
The enemy bombers appeared over Pearl Harbor at about 7.:55 a.m.
敵軍轟炸機凌晨 7：55現身珍珠港
December 7, 1 94 1--
1941年12月7日…
a date which will live in infamy--
給我們帶來恥辱的一天…
- Any contact with our planes? - No, sir.
-聯繫到我們的戰機沒有？ -沒有，長官
Keep trying.
繼續嘗試
- Dan, get me a damage report. - Right, Skipper.
-丹，去查看損毀情況給我報告 -是，艦長
- Get a phone check with all stations. - Yes, sir.
-電話檢查各位置情況 -是，長官
- You have control of the rudder. - Bridge has control of the rudder, sir.
-你掌方向舵 -指揮塔 現在控制方向，長官
- Very well. - All stations who experienced contact.
-好 -聯絡所有崗位
There they are! Lo, on the right!
他們在那！右邊！
Stand by to render honors to port U.S.S. Arizona.
為亞利桑那號停靠預備禮儀
Attention to port.
注意停靠
And salute.
敬禮
Two. Carry on.
2號，接著
Pacific Fleet arriving.
太平演艦隊到達
3rd Fleet arriving.
第三艦隊到達
Carrier Group 8 arriving.
第八組航母到達
Matt, what the hell's going on here?
馬特，這裡怎麼了？
Admiral, I don't know where to begin.
元帥，我也不知從何說起
Aircraft carrier getting lost in the Pacific Ocean.
航母在太平洋莫名消失？
What kind of navy is this?
這算什麼海軍？
He'll never believe it.
他一定不會相信
Captain, the admirals have departed.
艦長，眾位元帥已離去
Thank you.
謝謝
You seem to have a 40-year-old dog on your hands.
你手中的狗可應該有40歲了
Yeah, you could say that.
可以這麼說
- Good luck, Mr. Lasky. - Thank you, Mr. Thurman. Good-bye.
-順風，萊斯基先生 -謝謝，特魯曼先生，再見
You know, in a way, Captain, I think we're lucky.
艦長，在某方面看來 我們算是幸運
How's that?
怎麼說？
At least we came back to the same world we left.
起碼回到了原先生活的世界
Most of us have.
我們大多人如此
Did Commander Owens have any family?
歐文斯斯指揮官有家人嗎？
No one.
沒有
Lasky, you've been a pain in the ass.
萊斯基，你真是個 惹人頭痛的眼中釘
But I'm glad to have known you.
不過很高興認識你
Thank you, Captain. I appreciate that.
謝謝，艦長，我很感激
Good luck to you.
祝你好運
And you too.
你也是
Wait a minute, boy. Here, Charlie! Charlie, come back here.
等等，查理，過來！ 回來
Mr. and Mrs. Tideman would like you to join them.
泰德曼先生夫人 希望能送你一程
Mr. Tideman?
泰德曼先生？
Welcome back, Mr. Lasky.
歡迎回來，萊斯基先生
Laurel. Commander Owens.
勞拉，歐文斯斯指揮官
Please,join us.
請上車
We have a lot to talk about.
我們有好多話談